# Koji Tominaga

Centre for Ecological and Evolutionary Synthesis (CEES)
Department of Biosciences, University of Oslo
P.O. Box 1066 Blindern • 0316 Oslo • Norway
koji.tominaga@ibv.uio.no

### **Summary**

I am an environmental scientist with a specialisation in massive computing. My application fields to date have been **climate change**, **anthropogenic pollution**, **biogeochemistry**, and **freshwater systems**. My interests in computing and numerical methods include **machine learning**, **parameter estimation**, **quantification of modelling uncertainty** and **data visualisation**. Highlights in computing experiences:

- Simultaneous control of 1000 computing nodes,
- 3 HPC platforms (Notur/Norstore, Sharcnet, Amazon EC2),
- · Large data and file management (terabytes), and
- Advanced level skills in Unix, Python and R.

#### Education

2009–2013	PhD in Biology, University of Oslo
2007-2009	MSc in Environmental Science, Trent University
2003-2007	BSc in Environmental Science, Trent University

# **Academic Exchanges**

Feb–Mar 2009	Technische Universität München
Apr–Jun 2009	Norwegian Institute for Water Research

## Work Experiences

2013–current	Researcher, University of Oslo
2010–2013	Part-time Researcher, Norweigian Institute for Water Research
2006–2009	Research Assistant, Trent University
2007–2008	Teaching Assistant, Trent University
2008	Seminar Instructor, Trent University
2006–2007	Grader, Trent University
2006–2007	Technical Assistant, Kawartha World Issues Centre

### **Relevant Communications**

- [1] Couture RM, Tominaga K, Starrfelt J, Moe SJ, Kaste Ø, et al. (2014) Modelling phosphorus loading and algal blooms in a nordic agricultural catchment-lake system under changing land-use and climate. Environ Sci: Processes Impacts 16: 1588–1599.
- [2] Tominaga K (2013) Lake Modelling: an interdisciplinary context. PhD thesis, University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway.
- [3] Tominaga K, Finstad AG, Kaste Ø, Andersen T (2012) Future climate change impact on lakes in fennoscandia: A dynamic mechanistic approach. Otsu, Shiga, Japan. 2012 ASLO Aquatic Sciences Meeting. Oral presentation. Presenter.
- [4] Tominaga K, Aherne J, Watmough SA, Alveteg M, Cosby BJ, et al. (2010) Predicting acidification recovery at the hubbard brook experimental forest, new hampshire: Evaluation of four models. Environ Sci Technol 44: 9003–9009.
- [5] Tominaga K, Aherne J, Watmough S, Alveteg M, Cosby B, et al. (2009) Voyage without constellation: evaluating the performance of three uncalibrated process-oriented models. Hydrol Res 40: 261–272.

In total, I have 6 peer-reviewed publications, approxmiately 30 conference appearances, 4 times peer-reviewer contributions, and attended numerous international scientific meetings in 13 countries.